#Encodergasm Presents
～
The elders are going to be on the move.
（シン）長老たちが動き出します
そちらも危険です　急いでください
It is dangerous over there as well.
Please hurry.
～
What a foolish act you have done.
（マン龍(ロン)）とんだ道化を
やらかしたものだ
The fortuneteller told us thus.
占い師が こう言った
"The night of the red moon, the snake will slither..."
“赤い月の晩”
“蛇がその毒牙を振るおうと
恐ろしく速く走る”と
"...horribly quickly to make use of its venomous fangs."
You look so pitiful, Vicious.
（ソウ龍）
哀れに見えるぞ ビシャス
We have informed you of our decision that you cannot be our successor.
（ピン龍）“お前は
後継者には なれない”と―
われわれの決定は伝えたはずだ
The syndicate does not need corpses who cannot even fight.
（ビシャス）戦うこともできない
しかばねなど―
組織には必要ない
お前の その傲慢(ごうまん)さは
やがて全てを滅ぼす
That arrogance of yours will ruin everything in the end.
Take him to the punishment chamber.
連れていけ 裁きの広間へ
Kill me.
殺せ　今すぐに
Right now.
お前に死に方など選べはしない
You cannot choose how you will die.
十分に屈辱を味あわせてから
冥府へと送ってやる
After we let you have a good taste of humiliation...
...we will send you into the underworld.
（ビシャス）忘れるな
Don't forget...
蛇の毒は後からゆっくりと効く
...a snake's venom poisons slowly after the bite.
（ジェット）全く
Sheesh, that was the first time we screwed up so badly.
あんな へまをやらかしたのは
初めてだ
We never had anything like that before...
前は こんなことはなかったぜ
２人で やってたときはな
...when we were all alone.
All told, they screwed up our plans right to the end.
結局 あいつらには最後まで
調子を狂わされっぱなしさ
They really were like troublesome babies.
あいつらは手のかかる
赤ん坊みたいなもんだった
お前が女と子供が嫌いな訳が
よーく 分かったよ
I completely understand why you hate women and kids now.
（スパイク）
ベルモットの入れすぎだぜ
Too much vermouth.
ぐはあ
Who are they?
（ジェット）何もんだ？
ぐわああああ
リン
Lin?!
I'm Shin, his younger brother.
弟のシンです
Shin...
シン　そうだったな お前たち
That's right, you two were...
If you change sides, you won't be able to return to the syndicate.
こっちについたら
お前 組織に戻れないぜ
何があった？
What happened?
（シン）ビシャスは処刑されます
Vicious is to be executed.
He failed to pull off the coup, and has been put under restraints by the elders.
クーデターに失敗して
長老たちに拘束されました
You are in danger as well.
あなたも危ない
ジュリアさんも
And Miss Julia...
Julia is...?
ジュリアが？
タルシスの町です
ここは食い止めます
They're in the city of Tharsis.
I'll hold them off here.
行ってください
Please go!
I'll owe you one, Shin!
一つ 借りだ！ シン
I don't know what happened to Red Dragon...
（ジェット）レッド･ドラゴンに
何が起きたか知らんが―
いまさら お前の出番じゃないだろ
...but it's not really your problem now, right?
Vicious, Julia...
ビシャス　ジュリア
To me, both those names sound nothing but ominous.
俺には
物騒な名前に聞こえてならん
Just like a magic spell that opens a door that shouldn't be opened.
開けちゃあならん 扉を開く
まじないのようだ
You're...
お前は… うぐっ
（ドクター）じっとしてろ
Hold still.
You are no longer a member of the syndicate...
お前は もう
組織の人間じゃねえんだ
I know.
分かってるさ
You, too...
あんたも いいな？
Forget everything, including the fact that we came here.
俺たちが来たことも
何もかも忘れてくれ
What are you talking about?
（ドクター）何のことだ？
I'm just treating stray cats that wandered into the office.
わしはただ 迷い込んだ野良猫を
手当てしてるだけだ
Stray cats that I can't ever get rid of.
腐れ縁の野良猫をな
When this is over, I'm leaving the syndicate.
（スパイク）これが終わったら
俺は組織を抜ける
You'll be killed.
（ジュリア）あなた 殺されるわ
死んだことにするのさ
I'll let them say I'm dead.
I'll be waiting at the graveyard.  Of course, I will be alive.
墓地で待ってる
もちろん 生きた姿でな
I... can't come with you.
（ジュリア）私は―
一緒には行けない
Come with me.
（スパイク）来るんだ
We'll leave here.  We'll escape from this world.
ここから
この世界から抜け出すんだ
And then what are we going to do?
（ジュリア）そして どうするの？
We'll just live a life of freedom somewhere.
（スパイク）
どっかで自由に暮らすだけさ
夢でも見るようにな
Just like watching a dream...
Are you going to betray me?
（ビシャス）俺を裏切るつもりか？
この世界から抜け出すか？
Are you going to leave this world?
Vicious.
ビシャス
たとえ夢でも不可能な話だ
Even if it's a dream, that's an impossibility.
Are you going to kill him?
（ジュリア）彼を殺すの？
Yeah...
そうだ
...with your hands.
お前の手で
You stay alive...
生き残るか ２人で死ぬか―
...or you both die.
You can choose.
お前が選べる
So there is no place for me after all.
（母親）結局 どこにも
居場所なんてないのさ
誰が迎えに来たって
あたしゃ行かないよ 絶対
I won't go no matter who comes to pick me up.  Never.
I don't want to live a life where I'm always in someone's way.
邪魔にされるだけの暮らしは
たくさんだ
Mom!  I've been looking for you!
（パンチ）母さーん
捜したよ
A-Alfred...
あ アルフレッド
I told you to wait in front of the curry restaurant!
カレー屋の前で待っててって
言ったじゃないか
Sorry.
ごめんよ
It's all right.  I'm glad you came.
いいんだ　よく来てくれたね
（母親）
いまさら面倒 見てもらおうなんて
虫がいい話だよね
It sounds too good to be true that you can take care of me now.
母さん 俺が一緒に暮らしたいんだ
Mom, I want to live with you.
You found a job?
仕事 見つかったのかい？
Don't worry about that.
心配ないよ
What about your female co-host?
（母親）相方の女の子は？
（パンチ）うん？ 結婚するってさ
I heard she's getting married.
Something about this...
何だかねえ
Where are you now?
今 どこだ？
何でしょう？
What is it?
I'm heading out to the city of Tharsis.
（スパイク）
こっちはタルシスの町に向かってる
お前もそっちに向かえ
You should head that way, too.
Why?
（フェイ）なんでよ？
（スパイク）ジェット 一人じゃ
動きが取りにくい
It's hard for Jet to get around on his own.
脚 撃たれてるしな
Especially after getting shot in the leg.
I'm telling you to stop wandering around so much, and just come back.
ふらふらしてないで
早く帰って来いっつうんだよ
帰るって決めつけないでよ
冗談じゃないわよ
Don't just assume that I'm coming back!
You've got to be kidding!
I have a place to go back to!
私には ちゃんと帰る場所があるの
What's with that attitude?  Like he's all high-and-mighty.
何よ あの態度　偉そうに
What does he mean, Jet's by himself?  HE's there.  Ed and Ein, too.
ジェット 一人って
自分がいるじゃない
エドやアインだって
（ジュリア）助かったわ
You saved me.
お互いさま
Same here.
いい腕ね
You're a good shot.
これで賞金 稼いでたんだもの
I was getting bounties with it.
A bounty hunter?
賞金稼ぎ？
Although now...
今は… フーッ
ちょっと訳あって休業中
...I'm kind of on a break 'cause there's something going on.
あんたも結構 訳ありな感じね
You look like you have something going on, too.
It might be good to pair up with another woman.
（フェイ）女同士ってのも
いいかもしんないわ
どう？ 一緒に組まない？
How about it?  Wanna be my partner?
（ジュリア）私は―
I have... something to do.
やることがあるの
Oh.
そう
残念
Too bad.
Do you know any bounty hunter hangouts?
（ジュリア）
賞金稼ぎのたまり場って知ってる？
（フェイ）
フフ 誰かに賞金 懸けたいなら
聞いてもいいわよ
I can help if you want to put a bounty on someone.
（ジュリア）賞金稼ぎを捜してるの
I'm looking for a bounty hunter.
I'll drive you back.
（ジュリア）送るわ
あなた 名前は？
What's your name?
フェイ
Faye...
Faye?!
フェイ？
フェイ･ヴァレンタイン
よくある名前よ
Faye Valentine.
A common name.
あんたは？
What's yours?
ジュリア
Julia.
Julia?!
（フェイ）ジュリア？
It's a common name.
（ジュリア）よくある名前だわ
会えて良かった
I'm glad I met you.
（フェイ）私もよ
Me, too.
ねえ あんた どっかで…
Um, have I seen you somewhere?
もしも スパイクに会ったら―
If... you see Spike again...
あの場所で待ってると伝えて
...tell him that I will be waiting there.
そう言えば分かるわ
He'll know what I mean.
はっ！ あっ…
ずっと待ってるって
Tell him that I'll keep waiting.
なんで？
Why?
Good-bye, Faye Valentine.
さよなら フェイ･ヴァレンタイン
Why?
なんでよ
なんで知ってんのよ！
Why do you know...?!
まだ痛むか？
Does it still hurt?
（ジェット）
こんな話を知ってるか？
Do you know a story that goes like this?
（スパイク）ん？
A man injured his leg during a hunt.
（ジェット）狩りの途中で
脚にケガをした男がいる
治療の当てのない
サバンナの真ん中で―
In the middle of the savanna...
...with no means to treat the wound, the leg rots, and death approaches.
脚は腐り 死に神が忍び寄る
The man got onto the airplane that finally arrived...
やっと迎えに来た飛行機に
男は乗り―
...and there he sees a land of pure white below him.
眼下に広がる純白の世界を見る
The place glistening in the light was the summit of a snow-covered mountain.
光り輝く そこは
雪をかぶった山の頂だ
The name of the mountain was Kilimanjaro.
山の名前はキリマンジャロ
男は思う
The man thinks...
...that was where he was headed...
自分が向かっているのは
そこなんだと
...and?
（スパイク）で？
（ジェット）
俺は この話が大っ嫌いだ
I hate this story.
男は過去ばかり思い出す
Men only think about the past...
...right before their death, as if they were...
死に際で―
必死に自分が生きていた証拠を
探すようにな
...searching frantically for proof that they were alive.
引き返せ
Turn back.
You told me when we first met...
最初に会ったとき お前は言った
“俺は一度 死んだ男だ”ってな
...that you were a man who had already died once.
もう いいだろ
Just forget the past, okay?
（スパイク）女がいた
There was a woman.
俺は初めて
本当に生きている女を見た
For the first time in my life...
...I saw a woman that was truly alive.
そう思った
That's what I believed.
She was a piece of me I had lost.
あいつは
俺がなくした俺の片割れさ
She is my other half that I had longed for.
俺が欲しかった俺の
かけらなんだ
帰ってきたぞ
She's back.
（ジェット）うん？ 何が？
Hmm?  Who?
（ジェット）あーあ
Oh, man...
うちは修理工場じゃねえんだぞ
故障したときだけ戻ってくるなんざ
We're not a repair shop.
Don't come back just when you broke something.
Where is he?
（フェイ）あれは？
（ジェット）あれって？
He?
The one with the fluffy hair.
（フェイ）モサモサのほう
何だよ　スパイクって言やいいだろ
What, can't you just say you're looking for Spike?
どこ？
Where is he?
（ジェット）工作室にいるさ
He's in the workshop.
何だ しらばっくれやがって
What are you trying to hide?
スパイクに会いに帰ってきたのか？
You came back here just to see Spike?
（フェイ）
伝言 頼まれただけ　ジュリアに
I was asked to relay a message...
...from Julia.
うんっ？ おい 待て！
Hey, wait!!
（ボブ）ジェット 俺だ
Jet, it's me.
なんだよ　情報なら いらねえぞ
今はそんな状況じゃあ…
What, I don't have any information now.  We're not really able to...
（ボブ）無事だったか？
I'm glad you're all right.
焦ったぜ　かなり
やばいことになってるからな
I was worried.  It's getting to be pretty bad, you know...
About Red Dragon?
レッド･ドラゴンか？
ああ 組織の継承問題を巡って―
Yeah...
There was apparently a coup two days ago...
２日前に
クーデターがあったらしいんだが…
...concerning who was going to be the syndicate's successor.
結局は長老派が勝って―
In the end the elders won, and they're now out...
...to annihilate anyone who was involved in the coup.
クーデター側を根こそぎ
つぶしにかかってるらしい
お前の相棒も…
Your partner will also...
（ジェット）とっくだよ
Been there.
だが なんで
抜けた連中まで手をかける？
But why are they trying to get rid of those that already left the syndicate?
Anything against them will be annihilated, down to the very last seed.
（ボブ）
異分子は種の一粒までつぶす
それがあいつらのやり方さ
That's how they do it.
（ジェット）最低の理論だ
That's the worst logic I've ever heard.
とにかく逃げろ
警察も対処しきれん
Just run.
The police can't handle all of it.
火星を離れろ
Leave Mars.
“遅かりし”だな
Too late for that.
（スパイク）なんか あんのか？
You have something?
You look like you have some information.
（スパイク）情報があるって顔だぜ
いくらで買う？
How much will you pay for it?
I don't have any money.
金ならねえよ
（２人）うっ…
（スパイク）お前も
まずいときに戻ってきたもんだな
You sure came back at the worst time.
（フェイ）
あんたが呼んだんじゃなかった？
Weren't you the one who called me here?
Or... maybe they followed you here?
お前 つけられてたんじゃないか？
ま 早いか遅いかの違いだ
Oh, well.  It was gonna happen sooner or later.
うう 待ってよ！
Wait!
ええい えっ
（フェイ）ちょっと待って
Wait a minute!
I don't have any money.
（スパイク）金は ねえ
（フェイ）あの場所で待ってるって
She said she'll be waiting there.
She said you'd understand.
そう言えば分かるって
I don't get it.
分かんねえよ
ジュリアって女よ
It was from a woman named Julia.
誰かに狙われてた
Someone was after her.
追われてた
They were chasing her.
Jet, I can go at any time.
ジェット いつでも出れるぜ
You who caused a disturbance in our clan's affairs...
（マン龍）
万機を かく乱せしもの―
万機の意志に従い 処刑する
...by the will of the clan, you shall be executed.
Let me out, too!
こっちも出して
待て！ 右のスラスターが
まだ動かねえぞ
Wait!
Your right thruster isn't working yet!
The end is the same if we go down ship and all!
（フェイ）船ごとやられちゃ
一緒でしょうが！
言葉を残すか
Will you leave words?
形あるものを残すか
Or leave something material?
Nothing.
（ビシャス）何も
赤い涙を流すがいい
You shall shed red tears.
Spike, can you still fly?
（ジェット）
スパイク まだ飛べるか？
こっちは もういい　行け！
Don't worry about us.  Just go!
なくしたもんとやらを
つかんでこい
Go grasp that thing you had lost.
行け！
GO!
As of now, the leadership has changed hands.
（ビシャス）今から師父は交代した
これから全ての権威と象徴を
私が担う
From now on, I will dictate all authority and symbolism of this syndicate.
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（スパイク）
いろいろあったが 次で最終回だ
A lot of things have happened, but the next episode is the last.
（ジェット）ええ？
（フェイ）えっ？
（ジェット）長かったなあ
だよなあ
It sure was long.
The past is the past...
No use doing this...
（フェイ）過去は過去
未来は未来
（ジェット）長かったなあ
だよなあ
（フェイ）過去は過去
未来は未来
（スパイク）やっとって状況だよな
ジェット どうだ？
（フェイ）過去は過去
未来は未来
...and the future is the future.
So how was it, Jet?
（スパイク）やっとって状況だよな
ジェット どうだ？
（フェイ）
男は男 女は女
今は今
（フェイ）
男は男 女は女
今は今
（フェイ）
男は男 女は女
今は今
（ジェット）
これのおかげで俺はアインを
飼うはめになったんだよなあ
A man is a man, and a woman is a woman.
Because of you, I ended up raising Ein.
（フェイ）
男は男 女は女
今は今
かわいいなあ
やっぱり犬ってのはなー
（フェイ）
男は男 女は女
今は今
かわいいなあ
やっぱり犬ってのはなー
I am who I am, and you are who you are.
Dogs are really cute after all.
（フェイ）私は私
あんたはあんた
かわいいなあ
やっぱり犬ってのはなー
（フェイ）私は私
あんたはあんた
（スパイク）おい ジェット
Like it really matters any...
Hey, Jet.  Come on, you aren't...
（スパイク）おい ジェット
（フェイ）
ただ それだけのことよ
（スパイク）おい ジェット
（フェイ）
ただ それだけのことよ
（ジェット）でも 人に
あげちゃったんだよなあ
（フェイ）
ただ それだけのことよ
（ジェット）でも 人に
あげちゃったんだよなあ
（フェイ）
どうでもいいけど…
I wonder why we gave him away...
...listening to what I'm saying at all!
（フェイ）
どうでもいいけど…
（スパイク）ていうか全然
俺の話 聞いてねえじゃねえか
（フェイ）
どうでもいいけど…
（スパイク）ていうか全然
俺の話 聞いてねえじゃねえか
（フェイ）
エド どこ行ったの？
（スパイク）ていうか全然
俺の話 聞いてねえじゃねえか
（フェイ）
エド どこ行ったの？
（ジェット）おおー 何だっけ？
（スパイク）まあ いいや
（フェイ）
エド どこ行ったの？
Never mind.
Oh...  What was it?
（ジェット）おおー 何だっけ？
（スパイク）まあ いいや
Anyway...  Next episode: The Real Folk Blues, Part 2.
（スパイク）
というわけで 次回―
「ザ･リアル･フォーク
ブルース（後編）」
We'll see you again, somewhere.
また どっかで会おう
What?  This is the end?
（フェイ）えっ 終わり？